<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rouke&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://broersma.dev/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rouke&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>rouke@broersma.dev (Rouke Broersma)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rouke@broersma.dev (Rouke Broersma)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 20:39:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://broersma.dev/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Aks Private Clusters</title>
      <link>https://broersma.dev/azure-aks-private-clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 20:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rouke@broersma.dev (Rouke Broersma)</author>
      <guid>https://broersma.dev/azure-aks-private-clusters/</guid>
      <description>When using Kubernetes it is considered good practice to limit API server access as much as possible. However the default configuration on cloud providers  exposes the API server on the public internet. This is fine when you&amp;rsquo;re giving it a try but once you start using Kubernetes more seriously you will probably want to start locking down access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wsl and Vpns</title>
      <link>https://broersma.dev/wsl-and-vpns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 14:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rouke@broersma.dev (Rouke Broersma)</author>
      <guid>https://broersma.dev/wsl-and-vpns/</guid>
      <description>WSL does not play nice with VPNs and you likely will not realize this is the problem at first. Luckily the problem is usually easy to fix. Changing the MTU value of your WSL network adapter is a good start if you are having issues!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Dedicated Disks in Wsl</title>
      <link>https://broersma.dev/how-to-use-dedicated-disks-in-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rouke@broersma.dev (Rouke Broersma)</author>
      <guid>https://broersma.dev/how-to-use-dedicated-disks-in-wsl/</guid>
      <description>When you access Windows files from WSL there is a large price to pay. But if you have important or a lot of data you use in WSL it can be a problem to only use the WSL root filesystem you get by default. It lives only in WSL (with an awkward way to access it from Windows) and to me feels like temporary storage you could lose at any time. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if you could use an external or extra hard disk in WSL while not having to pay the price? Well, now you can!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Start Wsl in Linux User Home</title>
      <link>https://broersma.dev/how-to-start-wsl-in-linux-user-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 17:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rouke@broersma.dev (Rouke Broersma)</author>
      <guid>https://broersma.dev/how-to-start-wsl-in-linux-user-home/</guid>
      <description>While using the Windows Terminal with WSL and Ubuntu I was bothered by the fact that I would always start in my Windows user home. Luckily there are ways to fix that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Modules for Themes</title>
      <link>https://broersma.dev/hugo-modules-for-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 19:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rouke@broersma.dev (Rouke Broersma)</author>
      <guid>https://broersma.dev/hugo-modules-for-themes/</guid>
      <description>The hugo tutorial tells you to use git submodules for themes. However hugo has a better system for dependencies called modules. I&#39; ll show you how to switch from git submodules to hugo modules!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I chose Hugo</title>
      <link>https://broersma.dev/why-i-chose-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 20:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rouke@broersma.dev (Rouke Broersma)</author>
      <guid>https://broersma.dev/why-i-chose-hugo/</guid>
      <description>This blog is currently powered by Hugo, a static site generator built in Go. However this was not my first choice. Initially I was going to use Jekyll for the simple reason that I had heard of it before and it is what Github uses to power Github Pages.
Almost immediately I decided that while Jekyll seems fine to use I did not want to be limited to what Github natively offers, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
